This is the BBC.
这是英国广播公司。
This podcast is supported by advertising outside the UK.
该播客由英国境外的广告支持。
From global current affairs to art, science and culture,
从全球时事到艺术、科学和文化，
the documentary from the BBC World Service tells the world's stories.
这部来自 BBC World Service 的纪录片讲述了世界的故事。
Search for the documentary wherever you get your BBC podcasts.
无论您在何处获取 BBC 播客，都可以搜索该纪录片。
Hello and welcome to More or Less on the BBC World Service.
您好，欢迎收看 BBC World Service 的《或多或少》。
We're your weekly guide to the numbers in the news and in life.
我们是您了解新闻和生活中的数字的每周指南。
I'm Charlotte McDonald.
我是夏洛特·麦克唐纳。
Tonight at 10, the FBI has arrested a suspect in the worst leak
今晚 10 点，FBI 逮捕了最严重泄密事件的一名嫌疑人
of secret US intelligence documents in years.
多年来的美国秘密情报文件。
We're going live to the Pentagon.
我们将前往五角大楼进行现场直播。
That's where the spokesman Patrick Reiter is taking questions
这就是发言人帕特里克·雷特 (Patrick Reiter) 接受提问的地方
and speaking right now on the origins of leaked documents that have been made public.
现在就已公开的泄露文件的起源发表讲话。
Under arrest, a member of the Air National Guard
一名空军国民警卫队成员被捕
suspected in the unprecedented leak of America's secrets.
涉嫌史无前例的美国机密泄露事件。
The leaking of US intelligence documents and the arrest of a 21-year-old airman
美国情报文件泄露，一名21岁飞行员被捕
who authorities believe to be responsible has caused a media and diplomatic storm.
当局认为责任人是谁，引发了媒体和外交风暴。
Many of the documents, some of which are marked top secret,
许多文件，其中一些被标记为绝密，
paint a detailed picture of the war in Ukraine.
描绘了乌克兰战争的详细画面。
The leaks have been widely reported, including by US Channel Fox News,
这些泄密事件得到了广泛报道，包括美国福克斯新闻频道、
many of whose hosts have been critical of the American government's policy in Ukraine.
许多东道主一直批评美国政府在乌克兰的政策。
This is what Fox News prime time host Tucker Carlson had to say about what the leaks showed.
这是福克斯新闻黄金时段主持人塔克·卡尔森对泄密事件的看法。
The second thing we learn from these slides is that despite direct US involvement,
我们从这些幻灯片中学到的第二件事是，尽管美国直接参与，
Ukraine is in fact losing the war.
乌克兰实际上正在输掉这场战争。
Seven Ukrainians are being killed for every Russian.
每遇害一名俄罗斯人，就有七名乌克兰人被杀。
Ukrainian air defenses have been utterly degraded.
乌克兰的防空系统已完全退化。
Ukraine is losing.
乌克兰正在失败。
So, according to Tucker Carlson, the leaked presentation slides show
因此，根据塔克·卡尔森的说法，泄露的演示幻灯片显示
seven Ukrainians are being killed for every one Russian,
每杀死一名俄罗斯人就有七名乌克兰人被杀，
which would be a pretty shocking finding.
这将是一个非常令人震惊的发现。
If those figures were true, then it'd be pretty catastrophic for the Ukrainians
如果这些数字属实，那么这对乌克兰人来说将是灾难性的
because I'm not like a war expert, but when you defend your own land,
因为我不像战争专家 但当你保卫自己的土地时
you usually give a lot more casualties out than you take.
通常，你造成的伤亡比你承受的要多得多。
Arik Tola has been working on the leaked document story.
阿里克·托拉（Arik Tola）一直在研究泄露文件的故事。
He's director of research and training for Bellingcat,
他是 Bellingcat 的研究和培训总监，
an investigative journalism site that specializes in using open source intelligence.
专门使用开源情报的调查性新闻网站。
It's played a leading role in tracing the spread of the leaked documents
在追踪泄露文件的传播过程中发挥了主导作用
on social media platforms like Discord and Telegram.
在 Discord 和 Telegram 等社交媒体平台上。
The first job was to work out whether they really were US intelligence documents.
第一项工作是查明它们是否真的是美国情报文件。
They seemed legitimate, but there was one that appeared to have been altered.
它们看起来是合法的，但其中有一个似乎被改变了。
It was just one single document that was modified very crudely,
只是一份文件，修改得很粗糙，
and it's very obvious that it was fake.
而且很明显这是假的。
The fake document was the one that discussed Russian and Ukrainian casualties.
这份假文件讨论了俄罗斯和乌克兰的伤亡情况。
There is one single file that was modified related to casualty figures
有一个与伤亡数字相关的文件被修改
of the Ukrainian and Russian militaries.
乌克兰和俄罗斯军队。
This was modified over a month after the file was initially released on Discord,
该文件最初在 Discord 上发布后一个多月进行了修改，
and it was just some telegram channel, not like a Russian government source.
这只是一些电报频道，不像俄罗斯政府消息来源。
So this could be as simple as one pro-Russian user very crudely photoshopping
所以这可能就像一位亲俄罗斯用户非常粗鲁地进行修图一样简单
one section of one image to make Ukraine look worse and Russia look better.
一张图片的一部分让乌克兰看起来更糟，而俄罗斯看起来更好。
The numbers are off-center. They're not quite spaced correctly,
数字偏离中心。它们的间距不太正确，
and it's just kind of crude. It's as if I did it.
这有点粗糙。就好像我做到了一样。
So on the original, undocked image, the number of Russian troops killed
所以在原始的、未停靠的图像上，俄罗斯军队被杀的人数
is more than double the number of Ukrainian soldiers killed.
是乌克兰士兵阵亡人数的两倍多。
But on the crudely doctored slide, the Russian losses have been reduced
但在粗略修改的幻灯片上，俄罗斯的损失已经减少
and the Ukrainian troop deaths have been vastly increased.
乌克兰军队的死亡人数大幅增加。
So all of a sudden, Ukraine has a lot more deaths.
所以突然之间，乌克兰的死亡人数增加了很多。
But despite Tucker Carson saying the slides contain evidence of a 7 to 1 kill rate,
尽管塔克·卡森说幻灯片中包含 7 比 1 的杀灭率的证据，
even the doctored figures don't show that.
即使是经过篡改的数字也没有表明这一点。
We tried to get Fox News to give us any more information about this claim,
我们试图让福克斯新闻向我们提供有关此说法的更多信息，
but we received no response.
但我们没有收到任何回复。
Aric believes it doesn't matter whether the mistake was made by Carson
阿里克认为，错误是否是卡森所犯并不重要
or his producer, such an error should have been avoided.
或他的制作人，这样的错误本应避免。
If you're a producer on a TV show, you should theoretically be able to fact-check
如果您是电视节目的制片人，理论上您应该能够进行事实核查
the stuff that you're citing in your report,
你在报告中引用的内容
but some people are better at it than others, to put it politely.
但礼貌地说，有些人比其他人更擅长这件事。
Even if we can completely dismiss Tucker Carson's claim
即使我们可以完全驳回塔克·卡森的主张
about the casualty numbers in these leaked documents,
关于这些泄露的文件中的伤亡人数，
how reliable are the numbers that US intelligence are quoting?
美国情报部门引用的数字有多可靠？
The BBC's Russian service has been compiling a list of Russian service personnel
BBC俄罗斯频道正在编制一份俄罗斯军人名单
killed in the conflict.
在冲突中被杀。
Senior correspondent Olga Ishina says the US estimate of Russians killed in action,
高级记者奥尔加·伊希纳 (Olga Ishina) 表示，美国对在行动中阵亡的俄罗斯人的估计，
up to 43,500, seems to tally with their own work.
高达43,500，似乎与自己的工作相符。
She explained how they calculate their figures.
她解释了他们如何计算数字。
Our primary goal is to count all the Russian losses,
我们的首要目标是统计俄罗斯的所有损失，
so Russian personnel killed in action.
因此俄罗斯人员在行动中阵亡。
And we do so by gathering all the publicly available information.
我们通过收集所有公开信息来做到这一点。
So first of all, it's different media reports from different outlets in Russia,
首先，俄罗斯不同媒体的不同媒体报道，
heads of local schools, heads of local libraries, heads of villages,
当地学校的负责人、当地图书馆的负责人、村庄的负责人，
tiny regional newspapers.
小型地区报纸。
On top of that, we monitor Russian social media
最重要的是，我们监控俄罗斯社交媒体
and the relatives of a certain person who died during the invasion.
以及在入侵期间死亡的某个人的亲属。
And another very important source of information are different memorials,
另一个非常重要的信息来源是不同的纪念馆，
monuments and graveyards.
纪念碑和墓地。
So we have an opportunity to monitor the situation in over 60 cemeteries,
所以我们有机会监测60多个墓地的情况，
all over Russia.
整个俄罗斯。
So compiling that all together,
因此，将所有内容汇总在一起，
we currently have a database of 21,000 Russian servicemen
我们目前拥有 21,000 名俄罗斯军人的数据库
who were killed during the invasion.
在入侵期间被杀的人。
As we monitor the situation on the cemeteries,
当我们监测墓地的情况时，
we see that each time we get access there,
我们看到每次我们访问那里时，
we see all the names which were mentioned in the public domain.
我们看到了公共领域中提到的所有名称。
And on top of that, usually the similar amount of names,
最重要的是，通常有相似数量的名字，
which are clearly died during the invasion,
显然是在入侵期间死亡的，
but they weren't mentioned publicly.
但他们没有被公开提及。
Based on that, we think that our database has 50% less names
基于此，我们认为我们的数据库中的名称减少了 50%
than a real number of Russian military casualties figure,
比俄罗斯军事伤亡的真实数字，
which were buried in Russia.
被埋在俄罗斯。
So if currently we have names of 21,000 Russian soldiers killed in action,
因此，如果目前我们有 21,000 名在行动中阵亡的俄罗斯士兵的名字，
our assessment is that total number of Russian casualties,
我们的评估是俄罗斯的伤亡总数
so killed only, must be around 42,000.
如此算来，仅被杀的，必定有42,000人左右。
Fox News itself has been in the headlines in the last few days.
福克斯新闻本身在过去几天一直成为头条新闻。
It was due to defend itself in a giant defamation case
是为了在一场巨大的诽谤案中为自己辩护
brought by Dominion Voting Systems,
由 Dominion 投票系统带来，
who alleged that Fox aired false claims
谁指控福克斯发布虚假声明
that Dominion's voting machines helped steal the election from Donald Trump.
多米尼恩的投票机帮助从唐纳德·特朗普手中窃取了选举结果。
The case was settled at the last minute,
案件在最后一刻得到了解决，
but the day before it was due to start,
但在活动开始的前一天，
Fox News took out a full page ad in the New York Times with the headline,
福克斯新闻在《纽约时报》上刊登了一整版广告，标题是：
"Trusted Now More Than Ever".
“现在比以往任何时候都更值得信赖”。
It then goes on to list what it says are the TV networks most trusted for news.
然后，它继续列出了最值得信赖的新闻电视网络。
Fox News itself is at the top of the bar chart with 41%,
福克斯新闻本身以 41% 的收视率位居条形图榜首，
trailed by ABC News on 24%, CNN and CBS on 22%,
紧随其后的是 ABC News（24%）、CNN 和 CBS（22%），
NBC on 21% and MSNBC on 18%.
NBC 为 21%，MSNBC 为 18%。
So you might think that's pretty clear.
所以你可能认为这很清楚。
If you ask Americans which news channel they trust the most,
如果你问美国人他们最信任哪个新闻频道，
the answer is Fox News.
答案是福克斯新闻。
But actually, that is the opposite of what you find
但实际上，这与你发现的相反
according to Elliot Morris, a senior data journalist for The Economist.
《经济学人》高级数据记者埃利奥特·莫里斯 (Elliot Morris) 表示。
If you just ask Americans, which news network do you trust the most,
如果你问美国人，你最信任哪个新闻网络，
then Fox News actually scores very poorly.
那么福克斯新闻实际上得分非常低。
Whereas things like the BBC, ABC, CNN,
而 BBC、ABC、CNN 等
have about 40% of Americans saying those sources are very trustworthy
大约 40% 的美国人表示这些消息来源非常值得信赖
or somewhat trustworthy, Fox News scores closer to 30%.
或者说值得信赖的是，福克斯新闻的得分接近 30%。
And they have a lot more Americans saying they're untrustworthy
还有更多美国人说他们不值得信任
than those mainstream news sources.
比那些主流新闻来源。
So the reality seems to be pretty significantly different
所以现实似乎有很大不同
than the advertisement they took out.
比他们拿出来的广告。
So how does the advertisement suggest something so different?
那么广告是如何暗示如此不同的东西的呢？
Well, look at the small print.
嗯，看看小字。
It seems what Fox News has done is not ask one question,
看来福克斯新闻所做的并不是问一个问题，
but two questions.
但有两个问题。
Which of the following networks do you watch?
您观看以下哪些网络？
And then they've listed all of the major news networks,
然后他们列出了所有主要的新闻网络，
so Fox, ABC, CNN, Riot, a couple of others.
福克斯、美国广播公司、美国有线电视新闻网、Riot 等。
And then, well, they don't tell us how they did this,
然后，好吧，他们没有告诉我们他们是如何做到的，
but my read of them asking the second question is,
但我读到他们问第二个问题是，
among people who said they watched Fox News,
在那些自称看过福克斯新闻的人中，
they then asked which news network do you trust the most.
然后他们问你最信任哪个新闻网络。
And of course, if you watch Fox News,
当然，如果你看福克斯新闻，
it's one of the only pretty mainstream, right-leaning news networks in America.
它是美国唯一相当主流、右倾的新闻网络之一。
You probably don't trust the other news networks,
你可能不信任其他新闻网络，
which you think are too centrist or left-leaning.
您认为过于中间派或左倾。
So, Elliot's take on the advert is,
所以，埃利奥特对这则广告的看法是，
it shows Fox News is the kind of news channel
它表明福克斯新闻是这样的新闻频道
that attracts an audience that agrees with its political outlook and trusts it.
这吸引了认同其政治观点并信任它的观众。
It's the most trusted channel by its audience,
这是观众最信任的频道，
but one of the least trusted by the general population.
但也是最不受大众信任的国家之一。
We asked Fox News about the advert.
我们向福克斯新闻询问了这则广告。
They told us that the data is from YouGov.
他们告诉我们这些数据来自 YouGov。
We approached the Pwning Company, who say the data used
我们联系了 Pwning 公司，他们说所使用的数据
is for media companies to learn more about their audiences only.
仅供媒体公司更多地了解其受众。
And these are not the results of any recent, nationally representative survey.
这些并不是最近任何具有全国代表性的调查的结果。
That's it for this edition of More or Less.
这就是本期《或多或少》的内容。
We'll be back next week.
我们下周回来。
If you want to get in contact, you can email us at moreorless@bbc.co.uk.
如果您想联系我们，可以发送电子邮件至 moreorless@bbc.co.uk。
But for now, goodbye.
但现在，再见。
Exploring the events shaping our lives through original documentary storytelling.
通过原创纪录片故事讲述塑造我们生活的事件。
We'll hear arguments of a role against we.
我们会听到反对我们的角色的争论。
The documentary from the BBC World Service is a window onto the wider world.
这部来自 BBC World Service 的纪录片是了解更广阔世界的一扇窗户。
The security situation in Europe has changed in the last couple of years, dramatically.
过去几年，欧洲的安全局势发生了巨大变化。
Search for the documentary wherever you get your BBC podcasts.
无论您在何处获取 BBC 播客，都可以搜索该纪录片。
[music ends]
[音乐结束]